states = {
    "Alabama": "AL",
    "Alaska": "AK",
    "Arizona": "AZ",
    "Arkansas": "AR",
    "California": "CA",
    "Colorado": "CO",
    "Connecticut": "CT",
    "Delaware": "DE",
    "Florida": "FL",
    "Georgia": "GA",
    "Hawaii": "HI",
    "Idaho": "ID",
    "Illinois": "IL",
    "Indiana": "IN",
    "Iowa": "IA",
    "Kansas": "KS",
    "Kentucky": "KY",
    "Louisiana": "LA",
    "Maine": "ME",
    "Maryland": "MD",
    "Massachusetts": "MA",
    "Michigan": "MI",
    "Minnesota": "MN",
    "Mississippi": "MS",
    "Missouri": "MO",
    "Montana": "MT",
    "Nebraska": "NE",
    "Nevada": "NV",
    "New Hampshire": "NH",
    "New Jersey": "NJ",
    "New Mexico": "NM",
    "New York": "NY",
    "North Carolina": "NC",
    "North Dakota": "ND",
    "Ohio": "OH",
    "Oklahoma": "OK",
    "Oregon": "OR",
    "Pennsylvania": "PA",
    "Rhode Island": "RI",
    "South Carolina": "SC",
    "South Dakota": "SD",
    "Tennessee": "TN",
    "Texas": "TX",
    "Utah": "UT",
    "Vermont": "VT",
    "Virginia": "VA",
    "Washington": "WA",
    "West Virginia": "WV",
    "Wisconsin": "WI",
    "Wyoming": "WY"
}

questions = {
    "Easy": [
        {
            "question": "What is the primary greenhouse gas responsible for climate change?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Oxygen", "Nitrogen", "Carbon Monoxide"],
            "correct_answer": "Carbon Dioxide",
            "explanation": "The primary greenhouse gas responsible for climate change is Carbon Dioxide (CO2). While "
                           "oxygen and nitrogen are important components of the atmosphere, they do not contribute "
                           "significantly to the greenhouse effect. Carbon monoxide is a harmful gas but not a major "
                           "greenhouse gas."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which renewable energy source uses the sun's energy to generate electricity?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Wind power", "Hydropower", "Geothermal energy"],
            "correct_answer": "Solar power",
            "explanation": "Solar power is a renewable energy source that converts sunlight into electricity using solar panels or photovoltaic cells. Wind power harnesses the kinetic energy of the wind, hydropower uses the energy of flowing or falling water, and geothermal energy harnesses heat from the Earth's interior."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the process called when plants convert carbon dioxide into oxygen?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Decomposition", "Breathing", "Respiration"],
            "correct_answer": "Photosynthesis",
            "explanation": "The process by which plants convert carbon dioxide into oxygen is called photosynthesis. During photosynthesis, plants use sunlight, water, and carbon dioxide to produce oxygen and glucose as a byproduct. Decomposition and respiration are different processes that involve the breakdown of organic matter and the release of carbon dioxide."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the largest source of marine pollution?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Sewage", "Metal parts", "Chemical spills"],
            "correct_answer": "Plastic",
            "explanation": "Plastic is the largest source of marine pollution, including single-use plastics, microplastics, and discarded fishing nets. While sewage and chemical spills can contribute to marine pollution, plastic waste has become a significant environmental concern due to its widespread presence and harmful impact on marine ecosystems."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which gas is responsible for the depletion of the ozone layer?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Carbon dioxide", "Methane", "Sulfur dioxide"],
            "correct_answer": "Chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs)",
            "explanation": "Chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) are primarily responsible for the depletion of the ozone layer. Carbon dioxide, methane, and sulfur dioxide are greenhouse gases that contribute to climate change but do not directly deplete the ozone layer."
        }
    ],
    "Medium": [
        {
            "question": "What is the term for the gradual increase in the Earth's average temperature due to human activities?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Global cooling", "Ozone depletion", "Acid rain"],
            "correct_answer": "Global warming",
            "explanation": "The term for the gradual increase in the Earth's average temperature due to human activities is global warming. It is caused by the release of greenhouse gases, primarily carbon dioxide, into the atmosphere as a result of activities such as burning fossil fuels and deforestation. Global cooling, ozone depletion, and acid rain are different environmental phenomena."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which country is the largest emitter of greenhouse gases?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["United States", "India", "Russia"],
            "correct_answer": "China",
            "explanation": " Currently, China is the largest emitter of greenhouse gases, primarily due to its large population and industrial activities. While the United States, India, and Russia are also significant emitters, China's emissions surpass those of any other country."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the main cause of deforestation?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Wildfires", "Mining", "Urbanization"],
            "correct_answer": "Logging",
            "explanation": "Logging, the process of cutting down trees for commercial purposes, is one of the main causes of deforestation. While wildfires, mining, and urbanization can contribute to deforestation, logging for timber and clearing land for agriculture or development are the primary drivers."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which environmental organization is known for its Red List of Threatened Species?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["WWF", "Greenpeace", "Sierra Club"],
            "correct_answer": "IUCN",
            "explanation": "The International Union for Conservation of Nature (IUCN) is known for its Red List of Threatened Species. The Red List provides comprehensive information on the conservation status of various species worldwide and assesses their risk of extinction."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the process of converting waste materials into reusable materials called?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Incineration", "Landfilling", "Composting"],
            "correct_answer": "Recycling",
            "explanation": "The process of converting waste materials into reusable materials is called recycling. Incineration involves burning waste for energy, landfilling is the disposal of waste in landfills, and composting is the decomposition of organic waste into nutrient-rich compost."
        }
    ],
    "Hard": [
        {
            "question": "What is the term for the loss of a species from a particular habitat or from the entire planet?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Invasive species", "Species introduction", "Endemism"],
            "correct_answer": "Extinction",
            "explanation": "The term for the loss of a species from a particular habitat or from the entire planet is extinction. Extinction can occur naturally, but human activities such as habitat destruction, pollution, and climate change have accelerated species extinction rates."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the primary cause of ocean acidification?",
            "incorrect_answers": ["Oil spills", "Eutrophication", "Industrial pollution"],
            "correct_answer": "Increased carbon dioxide absorption",
            "explanation": "The primary cause of ocean acidification is the increased absorption of carbon dioxide (CO2) by the oceans. When CO2 dissolves in seawater, it forms carbonic acid, leading to a decrease in ocean pH levels and harmful effects on marine ecosystems."
        }
    ]
}

environmental_tips = [
    "Reduce your water consumption by taking shorter showers and fixing any leaks in your home.",
    "Switch to energy-efficient light bulbs to save electricity and reduce carbon emissions.",
    "Opt for reusable shopping bags instead of single-use plastic bags to reduce waste.",
    "Plant trees in your community to improve air quality and provide habitat for wildlife.",
    "Use public transportation, carpool, or bike whenever possible to reduce air pollution from vehicles.",
    "Conserve energy by unplugging electronics when not in use and adjusting your thermostat.",
    "Recycle paper, plastic, glass, and metal to minimize landfill waste and conserve resources.",
    "Choose organic, locally sourced food to support sustainable agriculture practices and reduce pesticide use.",
    "Compost food scraps to reduce methane emissions from landfills and create nutrient-rich soil.",
    "Educate yourself and others about environmental issues to promote awareness and inspire positive change."
]